JOSHUA CAVE



josh@nerdy.co.nz





github.com/nerdynz



in linkedin.com/in/joshuacave



SUMMARY

I bring 8 years of experience in full-stack applications, ranging from full-blown microservice architectures in golang and Vue.js to monolithic .NET/jQuery applications. I am a big believer in the best tool for the job and am always willing to adapt and learn something new.

Lastly, while I am comfortable working remotely, having done so for the past year, I am hoping to find a workplace that values a strong team focus and encourages pulling up a chair and working through a tricky problem together.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Developer - IQ Hive

March 2020 - Current

Working for IQ Hive as a backend developer on a few large projects in an effort to create a turn-key-telco solution which will be used by clients such as Vodafone, Plan-B and Vocus. The projects included integrations with Matrixx OCS, TCF Number Portability, Xero and a SIP Trunking integration via DCOM.

An overview of some of the microservices below:

- Integration with Matrixx Swagger REST API for provisioning Data Plans
- Integration with Matrixx ActiveMQ for Billing Events and publishing them into BigQuery via cloud tasks.
- Integration with Xero via swagger with Aggregation of above billing events
- Full workflow and polling solution following the TCF IPMS specification for porting numbers between carriers
- REST integration with DCOM API

All services communicated internally via gRPC and using protobuf serialization, the public facing APIs are exposed via a gRPC to REST proxy which follows an OpenAPI spec.

Digital Lead - Coastgroup

Feb 2019 - March 2020

Originally a client of NERDY through Displayworks. I was brought on to continue work on Shredder, an internal job system I built for Displayworks, retrofitting and improving it for use in other companies within the group.

Built on Vue.js and Golang I have since integrated with both Gsuite and MYOB drastically improving the workflow of the account managers.

I have also been in charge of improving their digital presence and launching new e-commerce sites on BigCommerce.

Responsibilities include:

- Working directly with managers of both Exhibition Hire Services and Show Light & Power retrofitting Shredder to suit their more event orientated businesses
- Launching new websites on BigCommerce for Exhibition Hire Services & Displayways
- Improving SEO and liaising with Pure SEO to improve digital presence across the group
- Working closely with designers and other team members on new content

Contracting on a weekly basis to Pengellys maintaining and improving their bespoke logistics system built on .NET and Classic ASP - with over 20 years worth of custom code that proved pretty challenging. I worked face to face with the client hot coding new ideas and deploying changes daily with an "iterate fast and release often" approach.

Noteworthy Features:

- Health & safety system
- Task and Corrective Action Report system
- Interactive KPI reports
- Client area with an interactive world map showing imports, exports and detailed product info
- A web-based document management system

Director - NERDY Nov 2017 - Feb 2019

Going at it alone. I found a niche in building job/invoicing systems for a small group of clients. I set out with NERDY using a completely new tech stack. Building full stack applications using Vue.js, backed by RESTful apis built in Golang using Postgres and Redis for storage.

Applications are hosted on self-managed VPS using Dokku and Git continuous deployments.

Lessons:

- Completely new tech stack
- Confidence to prototype and pitch ideas
- More accurate view on how long projects take
- More goal orientated mindset
- Better self-awareness/discipline

I also launched <u>Relapse</u> the time tracking application for OSX using Node.js, Electron, Vue.js and HTML5 canvas.

Senior Developer - beweb

Oct 2013 - Nov 2017

A web development company specializing in bespoke websites for digital agencies and key clients. Websites are built using .NET and backed by SQL server. I started as a junior developer and grew through the ranks, taking on every aspect of working with a close nit group of developers in a fast-paced environment.

I was also directly involved with the launch of a Cordova based mobile application <u>Speaking Email</u> - a subscription based email client that reads your email out loud.

Responsibilities included:

- Mentoring / Pair Programming with junior developers
- Liaising directly with clients
- Code reviews
- Maintenance of Codelib (core code library)
- Quoting / scoping new projects

EDUCATION

Unitec – Bachelor in Computing Systems 2013

Unitec – Diploma in Information Technology and Support 2009 – 2010

Gained award for top Diploma student in Information Technology and Support 2010

Unitec – Certificate in Information Technology 2009